

Supriyo Paul

Email: <u>paul.supriyo.paul@gmail.com</u>

Phone: 8340265344

Title: Software Architect, Python Developer, DevOps, Automation

Summary:

I am a tech-savvy person who has been interested in technology from an early age. I love learning new technologies and having new experiences. I spend most of my leisure time learning about new advancements in the tech world. I have a keen understanding of **backend architecture**, thanks to my experience in a variety of domains and multiple roles. **Cleanliness, quality, and automation** drive most of my development work. I also enjoy playing badminton and volleyball and watching anime and documentaries.

Experience:

Software Architect at Jio (Sep 2021 - Present)

- Building the domain agnostic Knowledge Graph and its CRUD APIs.
- Performance monitoring and enhancement of the Knowledge Graph system.
- Mentoring the team on best practises and the overall maintainability of the various repositories in the BrainOS ecosystem.

Data Engineer at Jio (Jan 2020 - Sep 2021)

- Building multiple robust clusters for log aggregation and testing the in-house cloud infrastructure platform JAWS.
- Maintenance and scaling of ELK and Kafka clusters across Jio businesses.

DevOps Engineer at AJIO.com (Sep 2019 - Jan 2020)

Supriyo Paul 1

• Building the Tools & Automation team that could help automate mundane, repetitive jobs across multiple teams in Ajio.

Associate Software Engineer at Deepcompute (Aug 2017 - Sep 2019)

- Worked across teams, developing open-source libraries and tools.
- Contributed to applications and helped teams with managing deployments, logs, and setting benchmarks for code quality for the codebase.

Education:

 Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science from Mallabhum Institute of Technology, Bishnupur (2013-2017)

Licenses & certifications:

- Al for everyone by DeepLearning.Al (Issued Aug 2022)
- Protocol Buffers 3 [Java, Golang, Python] by Udemy (Issued Jan 2022)
- Data Structures and Algorithms by Udemy (Issued Aug 2021)

Skills:

- **Technology concepts**: OOPs, NoSQL, Time Series Analysis, Graph Databases, Rest, Protocol Buffers (gRPC), DevOps, Containerization, Container Orchestration, CI/CD, Test Automation, Version Control (git), Documentation, Agile.
- **Programming languages**: Python, Bash, Markdown
- Database technologies: ArangoDB, ElasticSearch, MongoDB, SQLite, InfluxDB
- DevOps: Linux tools, Docker, Kubernetes, Azure DevOps, Ansible, Elastic Stack (ELK), Prometheus, APM, Nginx, Travis CI, Git
- **Dashboarding**: Kibana, Grafana
- Soft skills: Requirement gathering, Team Management, Team Building

Supriyo Paul 2